<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King a proclamation inhibiting all persons to repaire to His Maiestie for cure of the disease called, the kings euill, vntill Michaelmas next.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1636</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A22604</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 9059</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S123792</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">33150561</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 33150561</idno>
            <idno type="VID">28658</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A22604)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 28658)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1877:28)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King a proclamation inhibiting all persons to repaire to His Maiestie for cure of the disease called, the kings euill, vntill Michaelmas next.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings most Excellent Maiestie: And by the Assignes of Iohn Bill,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1636.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Arms with "C R" at top.</note>
                  <note>"Giuen at Our Palace of VVestminster, the seuenth day of April, in the twelfth yeere of Our Reigne."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Society of Antiquaries.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Scrofula --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Royal touch.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Charles I, 1625-1649.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="royal_proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:28658:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 20 -->
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <head>C R</head>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the King.</head>
            <head type="sub">¶ A Proclamation inhibiting all perſons to repaire to His Maieſtie for cure of the Diſeaſe called, The Kings Euill, vntill Michaelmas next.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas His Maieſtie by his Proclamation in Iuly laſt, did preſcribe</hi> the times of <hi>Michaelmas</hi> and <hi>Eaſter,</hi> for preſenting to Him for cure ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons as were affected with the Diſeaſe called, <hi>The Kings Euill:</hi> which His Maieſtie out of His gracious and pious diſpoſition to relieue their diſtreſſes, was wi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ling now at <hi>Eaſter</hi> accordingly to have done; Yet fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeeing the danger that may ariſe as well to His ſacred Perſon, as other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, by the concurſe of diſeaſed people from all parts of the Realme to His Maieſties Court, eſpecially at this preſent time, when as the infection of the Plague is diſcouered and broken out in ſome places of the Kingdome; His Maieſtie therefore timely to preuent the dangers thereof, as well to his owne Perſon, as to his people, doth hereby publiſh His Royall Pleaſure to be, And alſo ſtraightly chargeth and commandeth, That no per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons whatſoeuer, doe preſume to repaire to His Maieſties Court to be healed of that Diſeaſe at <hi>Eaſter</hi> now next comming; But doe wholly forbeare the ſame, vntill the Feaſt to Saint <hi>Michael</hi> the Archangel next following, (vnleſſe His Maieſtie ſhall hereafter declare any ſhorter time for that purpoſe) vpon paine of His Maieſties high Indignation, and to be puniſhed with all ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verity as Offenders in ſo high a nature. And His Maieſtie doth ſtraitly charge and command all Iuſtices of Prace, Maiors, Bailiffes, Conſtables, Headboroughs, and other His Officers and Miniſters whatſoever whom it may concerne, That they make ſtay of as many as they finde tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uelling or preparing themſelues to His Maieſtie for Cure, and that they ſuffer no perſons whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>euer to make their reſort to His Maieſties Court now at <hi>Eaſter</hi> next for that end, As they tender His Maieſties pleaſure, and will anſwer the contrary at their vttermoſt perils.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen at Our Palace of VVeſtminſter, <date>the ſeuenth day of April, in the twelfth yeere of Our Reigne.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
¶ God ſaue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprinted at London by ROBERT BARKER, Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie: And by the Aſsignes of IOHN BILL. 1636.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
